Jonathan C. Shelly

18 River St, Collinsville, CT 06019 T: 860 869 9490 E: JShelly@Windsorct.org

Summary

Passionate and energetic music teacher and jazz trombonist with diverse musical experiences teaching general music, beginner and advanced band/orchestra, composing and arranging band/choir music, teaching West African drumming, group piano, and facilitating an elementary Suzuki Violin program. Experience implementing Conversational Solfege, Orff, and Kodaly pedagogies.

Education

University of Connecticut, Neag School of Education

May 2011

Dual degree in Music Education: B.S. in Education and B.F.A.

with Jazz Emphasis Cum Laude: 3.69 GPA CT Certificate: 049

University of Missouri, School of Information Sciences and Learning Technologies

Currently Enrolled MS in Technology in Schools

Experience

Pre-K through 2 General Music and Choir, Oliver Ellsworth Elementary

Windsor, CT — 2014-Present

Elementary music position with a Conversational Solfege-driven curriculum.

- Currently teach 25 sections of music including 8 sections of Special Ed Pre-K.
- Direct a choir that performs biannual concerts and school assemblies.
- Awarded 2015-2016 Building Educator of the Year.
- Spent two years as PBIS coach, planning school-wide events and incentives, planning and running weekly committee meetings, analyzing and presenting data at staff meetings.
- Developed a deep understanding of PBIS behavior philosophies and strategies.

PreK-2 General Music and Violin, North Street School

Windsor Locks, CT — 2013-2014

School year substitute for a teacher on sabbatical.

- Presented concerts for Pre-K, K, 1, and 2, as well as a violin recital.
- Collaborated with the Art teacher to develop an interdisciplinary African Art and Music curriculum and performance that merged songs, drumming, and

art.

- Ran a successful Suzuki Violin program of nearly 50 K-1 students.
- Developed an after-school West African drumming enrichment program.

Band/Orchestra Director, The Master's School

West Simsbury, CT — 2011-2012

Director of beginner elementary, middle, high school bands, as well as chamber ensembles, including string quartets.

Substitute Teacher

Districts of Simsbury, Harwinton/Burlington: Region #10— 2012-2013

Per diem substitute teacher for most subjects, but mostly general music, band, choir.

Student Teaching: 5th and 6th Grade Band Instructor, Simsbury Public Schools

Additional Skills

- Able to accompany students on piano or guitar. Able to arrange all music to appropriately challenge and fit the specific needs of each student.
- Proficient on Sibelius (arranging software), SoundTrap, Garageband.
- Experience using Ipads and various interactive music education apps in the classroom.
- Studied jazz trombone in college, experience arranging for and directing 17-piece big bands.
- Experience teaching private lessons on all band instruments, violin, piano, and guitar.
- Experience tutoring ELL, reading, writing, and mathematics for ages 6 to 12.